John E. Hogan papers, Inclusive: 1916-1998, undated; Bulk: 1974-1998.
Baylor University, Baylor Collections of Political Materials
John E. Hogan papers
Inclusive: 1916-1998, undated; Bulk: 1974-1998.
Baylor University, Baylor Collections of Political Materials http://www.baylor.edu/lib/bcpm/
11
Hogan, John E., 1925 - 2012
24 document boxes and 1 oversized box.
The John E. Hogan papers span the length of Hogan's time working as counsel for the U.S. House Committee on Agriculture, from the 1970s to the late 1990s. Much of the materials are research materials accumulated for legislative purposes.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Excellent.
Biography/Profile
John E. Hogan was born on December 30, 1925, in Janesville, Minnesota. After graduating from the University of Minnesota, Hogan served in the U.S. Navy from 1950 to 1957, including service during the Korean War. Taking full advantage of the GI Bill, he transferred to Washington, D.C. and earned a law degree from George Washington University, a Masters in Law from Georgetown University, and a Masters in Business Administration from American University. Hogan remained in the U.S. Naval Reserve until 1983.
In 1969, Hogan started his tenure working with the U.S. House of Representatives. After serving as Minority Counsel for the House Committee on the District of Columbia (1969-1975), Hogan was appointed Republican Counsel for the House Committee on Agriculture (1975-1998). He served in various roles including Associate Minority Counsel (1975-1979) and Minority Counsel (1979-1995) before retiring in 1998.
In 2001, Hogan returned to D.C. to serve briefly as President George W. Bush's Active Deputy Under Secretary for the U.S. Department of Agriculture's Food Safety and Inspection Service.
Hogan married Edith Howard and had two children: Edith Chrystal Hogan and Terrence Howard Hogan. He died on November 7, 2012.
Scope and Content
The John E. Hogan papers cover 1916 to 1998, with some undated materials. The bulk of the papers are from Hogan's time serving as counsel for the U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Agriculture from 1975 to 1998. The papers mainly consist of Hogan's research, including Congressional Research Service reports, legislation documentation, correspondence, and other administrative materials. Some of the main topics addressed in the files include the 1990 and 1995 Farm Bills, the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA), and the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA).
The papers are divided into five topical series: Agriculture, Environment, Federal Law, Trade, and Richard Nixon Impeachment Materials. Series I. Agriculture is by far the largest series, constituting nearly half of the collection. Overall, the materials are in excellent condition.
Arrangement
The John E. Hogan papers were originally housed in 10 record storage boxes. There was some arrangement with similar topics located close together but not enough to warrant keeping the folders in the original order.
The papers have been rearranged and are now organized into five topical series: Agriculture, Environment, Federal Law, Trade, and Richard Nixon Impeachment Materials. Within each series, the folders are arranged alphabetically by title.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to the W. R. Poage Legislative Library in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 11. Acquired 2014-01-11
Related Resources
Items in related collections
William Robert "Bob" Poage Papers
Related references
John E. Hogan obituary. The Washington Post. Accessed April 20, 2021.
John E. Hogan papers, Accession #11, control file, Baylor Collections of Political Materials, W. R. Poage Legislative Library, Baylor University.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994 -- Trials, litigation, etc.
Subjects (Organizations)
United States. Congress. House. Committee on Agriculture--Officials and employees.; United States. Department of Agriculture.
Subjects
Agriculture -- United States.; Environmental law -- United States.; Foreign trade promotion -- United States.; Free trade.
Genres
Correspondence.; Legislative bills.; Legislative materials.
- Agriculture, 1916-1998, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Excellent.
  Biography/Profile
  The largest series in the collection, Series I. Agriculture, contains materials that deal primarily with farm bills, policies, and various crops. Proposed farm bills from 1990 and 1995 represent the most substance. The materials in this series are in excellent condition.
  - 1990 Farm Bill and Farm Cooperatives, 1976-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1990 Farm Bill, Center for Resource Economics, 1992 March (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1990 Farm Bill, Extension, Explanatory Materials (1 of 2), 1995 March (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1990 Farm Bill, Extension, Explanatory Materials (2 of 2), 1995 March (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1990 Farm Bill, Proposal of the Administration, 1990 February (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1990 Farm Bill, Questions and Answers, 1990 February (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1990 Farm Bill, Side-by-Side Comparison, 1990 September (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1995 Farm Bill, General, 1994 June (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1995 Farm Bill, Conservation, Grazing (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1995 Farm Bill, Farm Supports, 1989-1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1995 Farm Bill, Farm Credit, Proposals (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1995 Farm Bill, General Farm Commodities, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1995 Farm Bill, Issues, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1995 Farm Bill, Option, The Freedom to Farm Act and 30 Percent Normal Flex Acres (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1995 Farm Bill, Peanuts (1 of 5), 1938-1995 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1995 Farm Bill, Peanuts (2 of 5), 1938-1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1995 Farm Bill, Peanuts (3 of 5), 1938-1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1995 Farm Bill, Peanuts (4 of 5), 1938-1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1995 Farm Bill, Peanuts (5 of 5), 1938-1995 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1995 Farm Bill, Policies, Livestock and Cotton (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1995 Farm Bill, Sugar (1 of 4), 1938-1995 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1995 Farm Bill, Sugar (2 of 4), 1938-1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1995 Farm Bill, Sugar (3 of 4), 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1995 Farm Bill, Sugar (4 of 4), 1938-1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1996 Farm Bill, Estimate Production Flexibility Contract, 1996 April 26 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1996 Farm Bill, Marketing Assistance Loans, 1996 April 30 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1996 U.S. vs. European Union Spending on Agriculture Support (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - A Cleaner, Safer, Healthier America, 1996 August (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Agricultural Adjustment Act, Egg Marketing Order, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Agricultural Civil Rights and International Trade, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Agricultural Export Programs, Food Aid, and the Farm Bill, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Agricultural Issues, Briefing Book, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Agricultural Issues, Briefing Book, 1994 May (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Agricultural Market Transition Act Flex Contracts, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Agricultural Market Transition Program, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Agricultural Outlook, 1996 April (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Agricultural Speech Kit, 1990 February (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service, Commodity Fact Sheets, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service, Farm Program Fact Sheets, 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service, US Department of Agriculture, Fact Sheets, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Agriculture, Consumer and Food Bills, 1973-1997 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Agriculture, Consumer, Food, and Trade Acts and Bills, 1973-1997 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Agriculture’s Future on the Table at Iowa Summit, 1994 August (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Agriculture, Issues, Briefing Book, 1992 April (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Agriculture, Jurisdiction, 1987-1997 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Agriculture, Legislative History, 1985-1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Alleged Violations of the Hatch Act, Espy, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - An Overview of Major Budget Procedures, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Anti-Trust Cooperatives, General, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Anti-Trust Cooperatives, Clippings, 1979 (Box 25 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Assessing the Management, 1996 July (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Attorney-Client Privilege and the Right of Congressional Access to Documents for Oversight Purposes in the Case of Suspension of the Telephone Loan Programs by the U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Background Legislation for the 1995 Farm Bill, 1990-1996 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Background on Farm Commodities for the 1995 Farm Bill, 1989-1997 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Background Research and Educational Material for a Pilot Test of the Group Risk Plan for Soybeans, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Baseline, Fiscal Year 1999, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Bills Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Bovine Somatotropin (bST) Regulations, 1988-1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Budgets and Child Nutrition, 1990-1997 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cattle and Meat Packing Industry, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Cattle Producers Relief, 1996 April 30 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Clinton’s National Food Safety Initiative, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Committee Floor Considerations, Agricultural Market Transition Act, H.R. 2854 (1 of 4), 1996 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Committee Floor Considerations, Agricultural Market Transition Act, H.R. 2854 (2 of 4), 1996 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Committee Floor Considerations, Agricultural Market Transition Act, H.R. 2854 (3 of 4), 1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Committee Floor Considerations, Agricultural Market Transition Act, H.R. 2854 (4 of 4), 1996 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Committee on Peer Review Procedures, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Commodity Fact Sheets, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Comparing Levels of Farm Support Across Selected Commodities, 1995 July (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Congressional Oversight Manual, 1979-1991 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Conservation Compliance, Operation, Performance, and Issues, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Cotton and Sugar, 1989-1997 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Cotton Program, Step 2 Investigations, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Cotton, Rice, and Sugar Subcommittee Agreement, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Country of Origin Labeling, 1987-1997 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Crop Insurance, General, 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Crop Insurance, “Appendix G: Legislative History and Statutory Provisions of the Federal Crop Insurance”, circa 1985 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Crop Insurance, Federal Crop Insurance Reform and Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994, 1994 October 13 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Crop Insurance, Government Accountability Office, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Crop Insurance, Support Programs, 1994-1997 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Dairy History, 1970s-1980s, 1978-1985 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Dairy Industry, bST and Price Data, 1988-1995 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Dairy, Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact, 1996 May 30 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Dairy Sector: Marketing, Policies, and Programs, 1991-1996 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Dairy Surplus, History, circa 1982 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Data Request from House Agriculture Committee Staff, 1995 July (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Delegation and Appointment Issues Concerning National Dairy Inventory Management Board, 1991 July (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Delegation of Authority to Non-Government Entities, Poultry, 1934-1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Employee Handbook for the Office of House Committee on Agriculture, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Environment and Agriculture Results, 1992-1994 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Estimate of the Pay-as-You-Go Effects of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act, 1996 August (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Farm and International Trade Services, Agricultural Stabilization, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Farm Bill Histories, 1949-1995 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Farm Bill Issues, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Farm Bills, Research, and New Programs, 1990-1997 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Farm Commodity Program, Peanuts, 1995 March (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Farm Commodity Programs, Sugar, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Farm Commodities, Rural Development, and the 1990 Farm Bill, 1976-1996 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Farm Credit and Crop Insurance, 1995 March (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Farm Program Flexibility, Analysis, 1989 December (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Farm Subsidies and Commodities, 1990-1997 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Farmers Across the Nation Share Ideas and Concerns with House Agriculture Committee, 1995 May (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Farmer Mac, Federal Agricultural Mortgage Cooperation, 1995 March (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996, Implementation, Correspondence and Statements (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996, US House of Representatives, Conference Report (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Contracts, U.S. v. Winstar Corporation, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Federal Ecosystem Management, 1994 October (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Federal Election Commission and Campaign Funds, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Federal Government Management, Examining Government Performance as We Near the Next Century, 1996 September (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act, Cancellation Proceedings, 1995 September (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Federal Marketing Orders for Fruits, Vegetables, and Specialty Crops, 1995 March (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Federal Milk Marketing Order Reforms, 1996-1998 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Federal Research and Development, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Food Aid, Round Table on P.L. 480 Programs, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Food Aid, Subcommittee on Foreign Agriculture and Hunger, 1989-1993 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Food Industry Opposition to Testing for E. Coli, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Food Security, Legal and Economic Aspects, The Case for Japanese Rice, 1990 May (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Foreign Sugar Imports, 1983-1994 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Full Committee Markup of 1985 Farm Bill, H.R. 2100 (1 of 5) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Full Committee Markup of 1985 Farm Bill, H.R. 2100 (2 of 5) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Full Committee Markup of 1985 Farm Bill, H.R. 2100 (3 of 5) (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Full Committee Markup of 1985 Farm Bill, H.R. 2100 (4 of 5) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Full Committee Markup of 1985 Farm Bill, H.R. 2100 (5 of 5) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - General Accounting Office v. National Cotton Council, On Cotton, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - General Farm Commodities, General, 1995 February (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - General Farm Commodities and Credits: Wheat, Feed Grains, Rice, Cotton, and Dairy, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - General Farm Commodities and the Federal Agriculture Reform Act, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - General Farm Commodities, Wheat, Feed Grains, Oilseeds, Rice, and Cotton, 1995 February (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Generic Advertising for Farmers, 1996 June (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Government Performance and Results Act, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Government Performance and Results Act of 1993, 1996 October (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Graduate School, Department of Agriculture, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Grazing Law, Proposals and Options, 1995-1997 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - H-2A Agriculture Guestworker Program, 1997 December (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Hearings on Teaching the Agricultural Sciences, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - House Agriculture Committee, “AG School” Seminar, 1995 March (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - House Agriculture Committee, Bills and Hearings, 1969-1980 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Imports, Exports, Trade, and Food Aid, 1989-1997 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Improving the Safety of Meat and Poultry, 1996 July (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Inclusion of Title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (H.R. 9), 1995 July (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Joint Venture between General Motors and Toyota, 1984 February (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Labeling, Ground Meat, 1993 August 27 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Law Research for 1996 Farm Bill, 1995-1996 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Legislation for Improving Seafood Inspection, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Livestock, Dairy and Poultry, Situation and Outlook, 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Livestock, Dairy, Marketing Orders, 1991-1998 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Lobbying Rules and Violation Inquiries, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - March 1996 Conference Report, 1996 March (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Motion to Direct Action by the Chairman, 1996 February (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, 1996 November (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - National Oceanic Program, 1990-1997 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - National Research Council, Board on Agriculture, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - National Summaries of the 1990-1995 Compliance Reports (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - New Food and Drug Administration Seafood Inspection Program, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - New Tools for Commercial Banks in Rural America, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - New Zealand Dairy Board Monopoly, A Destabilizing Factor in U.S. Dairy Product and Milk Markets, 1995-1996 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Note Passing during Investigative Hearing, 1996 September (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Nutrition Labeling, Sugar Crops, 1985 Food Security Act, Telecommunications, 1985-1995 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Organization and Home Rule for District of Columbia, 1972-1974 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Peanut and Wheat Changes, 1990 July (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Peanuts, Competitive Enterprise Institute, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Peer Review and Credibility in Tennessee Valley Authority Environmental Research and Development, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Perishable Agricultural Commodities Act, Lang and Finks v. Kornblum, 1995-1996 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Policy Alternatives Relating to Agricultural Trade Options, 1997 May (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Policies for Different Farm Crops, 1990-1996 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Property Rights, Federal Law, and the Line Item Veto Act, 1995-1996 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Proposed Resolution Regarding Sale of Tobacco, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Reforming Farm Crops Programs, 1971-1997 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Repealing the Sugar Program, 1995 March (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Research and Promotion Programs Authorized by Individual Statutes, 1995 January (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Reverting to the Agricultural Act of 1949 for Specific Commodities, 1990-1996 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Review of U.S. Trade Representative's and U.S. Department of Agriculture's List of Promises, 1995 December (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Rules of the Committee on Agriculture, 1996 November (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Rules of the Committee on Agriculture (with Revisions), 1987-1996 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Rural Development, 1995-1996 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Rural Development Policy (1 of 2), 1980-1984 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Rural Development Policy (2 of 2), 1980-1984 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Selected Rural Development Programs in the Department of Agriculture, 1995 March (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Standing to Sue and the Animal Welfare Act, 1987-1990 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Step 2, Audit Background, 1995 November (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Step 2, Cotton Program, Its Failure Exposes Flawed U.S. Cotton Policy, 1995-1996 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Sugar History, 1971-1978 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Sugar History, 1979-1983 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Sugar Marketing Allotment Issues, 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Tobacco Programs, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The Existence of a Contract with the Government, 1996 January (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - United States Grain Standards Act, 1988-1990 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - United States Grain Standards Act of 1916, 1916 August (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Updating Policies and Programs, Dairy, Meat, Poultry, and Seafood, 1979-1998 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Updating Various Agricultural Laws, 1990-1997 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Upland Cotton, Freedom to Buy, Special Import Program, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - U.S. Agriculture and a New Farm Bill, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - “U.S. Agriculture: Myth, Reality, and National Policy”, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - U.S. Food and Agriculture Research System, 1982 January (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - U.S. Grain Standards Act, 1992-1997 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - U.S. House of Representatives Employee Handbook, 1996-1997 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - U.S. Peanut Program and Challenges Faced, 1994-1996 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - U.S. Rice Exports: Comparison of U.S. and Thailand’s World Export Market Shares, 1988 December (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - U.S. Sugar Policy and the Australian Sugar Experience, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - U.S. Sugar Research, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture Announces Quarterly Revision of Sugar Marketing Allotments for Fiscal Year 1995, 1995 April (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture, Equity Analysis of 1985 and 1990 Farm Legislation, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture, Financial Systems, 1995 September (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture, Telecommunications, 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Environment, 1974-1997, undated; 2
  Series II. Environment consists of materials that address various facets of the relationship between agriculture and environmental safety. The materials cover such topics as conservation, endangered species, food safety, forestry, pesticides, and wetlands. Several pieces of legislation, including the Food Quality Protection Act of 1996 and the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (FIFRA), feature prominently. Overall, the series is in excellent condition.
  - Air Quality, Clean Air Act, Clippings and Reports, 1990-1997 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Clean Water, Congressional Research Service, Water Quality Issues, Reports, 1996-1997 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Clean Water, Separation Sheets, Publications, 1991-1997 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Congressional Tour, Plum Creek Timber Company Lands, Report, 1997 August 12 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Conservation, 1996 Farm Bill, Report, “Soil Loss Equation Federal Register Notice” (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Conservation, Conservation Reserve Program, Baseline Assumptions, Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Conservation, Conservation Reserve Program, Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Conservation, Conservation Reserve Program, Press Releases, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Conservation, National Conservation Buffer, Briefing and Packet, 1995-1997 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Conservation, Water Quality Incentives Projects, Fact Sheets and Reports, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Department of Agriculture, Report, “Educational Programs in Support of Ecosystem Management”, 1994 March 24-25 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Department of Agriculture, Report, “Risk Management — New and Specialty Crops”, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Disaster Assistance, Drafts, 1996 April 29 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Endangered Species, Endangered Species Act of 1995, Clippings and Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Endangered Species, Endangered Species Act of 1995, Pamphlets and Summaries, 1993-1994 (Box 12, Folder 15)